Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
The Gaw formation from North America,
led by Captain Char...
...carried out a surprise attack against
the Earth Federation Headquarters at Jaburo.
However, with the efforts of
the Gundam and others...
...the Federation Forces fought back hard
and the enemy was forced to retreat.
But will Char really give up so easily?
A Wish of War Orphans
Point B-3! Thus far, we have
nothing out of the ordinary to report.
Just regular Zeon bombings, as usual.
Roger!
What's the point in regular reports
from a remote outpost like ours?
Don't complain so much!
Those guys aren't doing their patrols
just to earn a paycheck.
What's wrong?
Another regular bombing, is it?
Well, it's nothing to be concerned about.
Now then...
The White Base's crew organization
will remain as it is now.
You'll be assigned to the
13th Autonomous Corps of the Tianem fleet.
I will now announce each of your ranks.
Lieutenant Junior Grade Bright Noa.
Yes, sir!
Ensign Mirai Yashima.
Yes, sir.
Petty Officer Sayla Mass.
Before we've even thought about It,
we've been made into soldiers.
Chief Petty Officer Amuro Ray.
Yes, sir!
Corporal Kai Shiden.
Yes, sir.
Corporal Hayato Kobayashi.
Yes, sir!
I haven't received anything like this
since my grade school diploma.
What good will this do?
Private 1st Class Fraw Bow!
Private 1st Class Fraw Bow? Isn't she here?
- Nooo!
- We don't wanna!
Come back here, you...!
Oh no. Please excuse me.
No way! I'm not going anywhere!
Me neither!
No way are we leaving!
What was that all about?
Well, the children absolutely refuse
to go to the childcare center, and...
How self-centered.
I have some expertise in this area.
I'll convince those children.
Ah, you should come with me.
Yes, ma'am.
Hurry up and receive your appointment.
Uh, yes sir.
Ryu Jose has been promoted two ranks
for honorable death in the line of duty.
He's been appointed lieutenant junior grade.
All other casualties have also
been promoted two ranks. That is all.
Promoted two ranks?
Promoted two ranks... ?!
Promoted two ranks... ?
Is... Is that all they get?
Huh?
They get promoted two ranks, and that's it?
That's the end of the matter?
What? What exactly are you saying?
You do nothing for us while we're fighting...
...and afterwards you hand out ranks.
Couldn't you at least say "thank you"
to Mr. Ryu and the others?!
Amuro. That's enough.
How dare you!
Who said you could dodge my blow?!
Do that again and I'll put you in solitary!
What?
There!
Well, you do say things that you shouldn't.
An occasional smack is good medicine.
Yeah. I get the message. Let's just drop it.
But what about Kikka and the others?
They were told the facility has
lots of fun playgrounds.
So they went with the childcare officer.
But I wonder...
Do you think those kids will
really be happy if they stay here?
Really be happy?
I think they'll be fine wherever they end up.
Do you really believe that?
We've got no choice.
They've gotta stay behind.
But...!
Little children shouldn't have to see
people killing each other.
Maybe you're right.
The preparations are done, Captain Char.
Okay! Let's go!
Juice! Juice! Delicious juice!
I want soft-serve!
You guys are so innocent and carefree.
Huh?
What's wrong with kids being carefree?
But all that does is make adults happy.
You are one cynical kid!
If you stick around here long enough,
you'll all end up like this.
There's a war going on right now!
Nothing to do with me.
All I do is sit around waiting until
my mother and father come and see me.
Mommy...?
Daddy?
Aw, cut it out!
But...
Why you...!
Ow!
Fraw! I wanna go home!
I wanna go back to the ship!
Look what you did!
This is all your fault!
M-Me too...
I wanna go home. I wanna go...!
What's wrong, kids?
She's coming!
Let's run away!
Right! Now, Kikka. Let's run!
Okay...
Hey! Come back here!
Katz! Letz! Kikka!
Where are you going?!
Come back, you kids! Can't you hear me?
Please answer me, Kikka dear!
Katz! Letz!
What am I going to do?
Somebody's coming.
Wait. They're kids.
Come on, Kikka.
Okay!
It's slippery, Katz. So be careful.
Katz!
Yeah.
They sure gave me a scare.
Captain Char?
The Federation's come a long way.
This is probably just a small sample
of what they have.
Are we doing it now? Captain?
Yes, of course...
Ramuji. Have your team set them here.
Sir.
Akahana, our teams will head
to the Trojan Horse's dock.
Right!
Ha! This'll be a piece of cake.
Keep running! If they catch us,
they'll take us back there!
I can't run anymore!
Kikka! Pull yourself together!
I wanna rest!
Well, if we have to...
Hey. This door opens.
It does? Okay, Kikka.
We'll rest here for a little bit.
Then we'll go back to the ship.
How much longer?
Sir, five more minutes!
Wait! Hide!
Sir?
Stinky.
Is there nobody here?
Hey! Look, Gundam's!
Oh, wow!
So many!
But it's kinda different from Gundam.
Come to think of it, they're a lot different.
Oh! Something's near its feet!
Huh? Near its feet?
I saw something move.
What?!
You imagined it. I don't see anything.
But it's true!
Something really moved!
It could've been a person!
- What?! A person?! Then we're in trouble.
- L-Let's hide.
Okay!
- Run away! Run away!
- The other way!
I know how you feel
but it'll make it tougher, Fraw.
But I'd just like to see them once more.
Even if it's just from a distance.
Huh?
That's the childcare officer!
Oh, I'm glad I found you now!
Kikka and the others have all run away!
What?!
Don't think ill of us, kids.
I've set them to detonate in 30 minutes.
Okay. Let's go!
Bombs!
They're b-b-bombs!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
Sorry for the wait.
We're finally authorized.
That's terrific! Now we can go on the tour!
You're coming too, right, Mr. Kai?
To the Gundam factory?
Ah, sure. I'll go to take my mind off things.
Lieutenant Bright.
Report to the operations room at once.
Coming, sir.
Well, that's the military for you.
You guys go ahead without me.
Okay.
You'll enjoy it more without your superior.
I did it! Katz, hurry!
You saved me!
W-We gotta get rid of those bombs!
Right!
Katz! Kikka! You two look under here!
Okay!
Um... Let's see...
Well? Any bombs??
Hey! Did you find any?!
Um...
No good! At this rate,
we'll blow up along with them!
I don't wanna! What should we do?
I found one!
What?!
This one's a bomb, right?!
Th-There's one over here, too!
Here we go...
Kikka, hurry up!
Come on! Start, engine! Start!
H-Hurry up!
I'm... I'm trying, but this thing won't start!
But are you sure you know
how to make it move?
I'll manage!
I did it! It started!
Okay, next I need to do...
This!
No. That wasn't it.
Those voices were Katz and Letz!
What are they doing in a place like this?
We gotta go after them!
Right!
Stop the car, Katz! Stop the car!
Amuro!
What are you doing here?!
Zeon set some bombs!
We're throwing them away!
Bombs?
Th-This is... Amuro, looks like it's true.
These are time bombs.
Where did you find them?!
Inside the Gundam factory!
All right, Letz. Get in the other car
and leave the rest to me. Hurry!
Okay!
Mr. Kai! Help the kids into the car!
Just leave it to me.
Okay, Letz! You go first!
- C'mon!
- Okay.
kay.
Okay, don't be scared. On three...
See, I told you it was fine!
Okay! You're next, Kikka. There!
Now it's your turn! Here we go!
You all did good. All yours, Amuro!
Thank you, Mr. Kai!
We did it! Yay! We did it!
The White Base is in danger!
Whoever set these bombs
will likely attack the White Base too!
Sounds like Ramuji's team went all out.
Ivanov. Can you hear me?
Yes, Captain Char.
Our mission has failed.
Distract the enemy with the Acguys.
Understood, sir.
Let's go!
It's starting to look rough up ahead.
The enemy's attacking with mobile suits.
That's...!
Katz!? Kikka!
Letz!
- Katz! Letz! Please answer me!
- Kikka! Where are you?!
Kikka!
Katz! Letz! Kikka!
Artesia
I thought so.
I... I never would have thought you'd join Zeon.
Not my gentle brother Casval!
Will you leave the military for me, Artesia?
Sayla! Are you there?
Please answer me...
Got that?
Casval!
Sayla!
Where are you?! Kikka!
Sayla?
Oh!
I heard gunfire... Was there a Zeon soldier?
Was there a...?
There was a Zeon officer here on this rock.
You didn't notice?!
I'm sorry...
Maybe we shouldn't go that way, then.
Captain Char...
Ignore them. We're all leaving.
Our mission is a failure,
so we're withdrawing. Got that?!
Sir!
Here I go!
I won't let you get away!
Four or five mobile suits... that's nothing!
Captain Char...!
Captain! lvanov's Acguy
has been destroyed!
Don't stop!
If you stop, you won't survive!
Keep moving!
Char!
I'll get you!
He's still coming?!
Coming!
Even though they're Acguys,
he took out four of them all at once.
He's improved his skills.
An underground water vein.
I, I can't see...
Knowing Char, he must have
used that opportunity to escape.
I understand how you feel.
However, they're guaranteed to be safe here.
Besides, the children are the future
of the Federation Forces...
...so they're brought up with great care.
Even after what happened today?
Also, when I consider their feelings,
I'm not sure these kids...
And you called them the future
of the Federation Forces, but...
...They might see a world without Zeon
or Federation Forces within their lifetime.
Can't you consider that possibility?
Our little rascals here
aren't your average children.
In all this time
they've seen plenty of gunfire...
...and they've been fighting with us
through those battles.
They've seen some terrible things
even an adult like you couldn't imagine.
And they never turned away their eyes.
You understand?
They don't wanna leave us. Right?
Yeah!
But... but they...
Yes. I suppose you may be right.
I'll make all the necessary arrangements.
- Then... then... It's so wonderful!
- Yeah!
This is great!
Now we can keep on bickering!
That's right!
Meanwhile, due to Char's guerrilla attack,
the Earth Federation Forces...
...have decided to speed up their space campaign.
The admirals have figured out...
...that Zeon has a high opinion
of the White Base's abilities...
...and so it would make an ideal decoy.
Are you saying that the 13th Autonomous Corps...
...will specialize in decoy operations?
The White Base takes off into space...
...where an immense battlefield awaits.
Char's relentless pursuit...
...eventually leads to fleet combat.
Will the approaching giant tear
the mobile suit to pieces?
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
A Decoy in Space.
Next Time
A Decoy in Space
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...